<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Robotics | Portfolio</title><link>https://eidanerlich.github.io/tag/robotics/</link><atom:link href="https://eidanerlich.github.io/tag/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Robotics</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://eidanerlich.github.io/media/sharing.png</url><title>Robotics</title><link>https://eidanerlich.github.io/tag/robotics/</link></image><item><title>Carl Bot, a robotic chess robot</title><link>https://eidanerlich.github.io/project/carlbot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eidanerlich.github.io/project/carlbot/</guid><description>&lt;p>Creating &amp;ldquo;Carl Bot&amp;rdquo;, a robotic chess robot, proved to be a captivating and challenging journey. Tasked with integrating game logic and movement on a chessboard, my team and I harnessed diverse technologies to achieve our vision. Named after world champion Magnus Carlsen, &amp;ldquo;Carl Bot&amp;rdquo; utilized Lego components for mechanical assembly, providing both customization and ease of setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To enable decision-making abilities and movement, we employed C++ and RobotC to program the robot&amp;rsquo;s logic. The true innovation lay in the ski system, featuring a mounted pulley for x-y movement and an actuator for vertical claw movement, ensuring precise and fluid manipulation of chess pieces. To further enhance accuracy, we incorporated motor encoders, sensors, and actuators, ensuring seamless control over the claw&amp;rsquo;s movement, making piece selection and movement effortless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The result was an impressive robotic chess robot, capable of executing precise moves, identifying chess pieces, and even evaluating basic game logic. The project&amp;rsquo;s resounding success showcased our dedication and skill in robotics and programming. Witnessing &amp;ldquo;Carl Bot&amp;rdquo; come to life in all its sophistication and precision was an immensely rewarding experience, validating our hard work and problem-solving prowess. The integration of multiple sensors and motors played a pivotal role in making &amp;ldquo;Carl Bot&amp;rdquo; robust and versatile, ready to tackle complex chess challenges with ease.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Autonomous Machine Vision Algorithm</title><link>https://eidanerlich.github.io/project/tmmc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eidanerlich.github.io/project/tmmc/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of the Toyota Innovation Challenge, I successfully built an autonomous machine vision algorithm in a simulated manufacturing environment, utilizing C++ object-oriented programming and cutting-edge computer vision libraries like OpenCV to track a 1:24 scale car model, identify its wheels, and provide real-time positioning data using a depth camera, enhancing manufacturing processes with optimal efficiency and precision. Moreover, I implemented an advanced event trigger system for dynamic capabilities and devised a custom formula to convert radial data into real-world positions, while the addition of dynamic visual feedback improved interpretability and troubleshooting, making it a standout and rewarding project in computer vision and OOP. Notably, our team was one of only three that successfully completed all the objectives in the challenge, solidifying our position as top performers in the competition.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fully electric Go-Kart</title><link>https://eidanerlich.github.io/project/go-kart/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eidanerlich.github.io/project/go-kart/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a collaborative team effort, we embarked on an ambitious project to design and fabricate an electric go-kart, making the most of available tools and materials. Leading the design phase, I meticulously crafted the go-kart using Computer-Aided Design (CAD), ensuring precision and efficiency in the manufacturing process. Employing scrap metal and leftover materials from previous projects, we embraced a sustainable approach that not only saved costs but also exemplified our commitment to recycling and repurposing, minimizing waste and maximizing resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Innovative thinking and diligent planning played a pivotal role as my partner and I brainstormed ideas, sketched designs, and created detailed CAD mock-ups. To bring our vision to life, we pitched the project to our school and successfully secured the funding required for its realization, despite facing tight budgetary and deadline constraints. I spearheaded the selection and sourcing of critical components, such as motor controllers, batteries, and mechanical modules, demonstrating a keen eye for balancing performance with cost-effectiveness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Integrating the electronic controls seamlessly with the custom powertrain, I optimized the go-kart&amp;rsquo;s power-to-weight ratio, resulting in a remarkable 150% power increase. The go-kart effortlessly reached high speeds while maintaining exceptional maneuverability, offering an exhilarating and dynamic driving experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The final product was a stunning yet resourceful electric go-kart, elegantly showcasing our engineering prowess and passion for motorsports. The sense of accomplishment upon seeing our hard work materialize into a fully functional and stylish mode of transportation was immensely gratifying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our go-kart stood as a testament to the potential of sustainable engineering practices and the fusion of innovation and creativity. This project allowed me to combine my passion for engineering and motorsports, furthering my personal and professional growth. I take great pride in the successful outcome and the valuable skills honed throughout the process. Working on this project alongside a dedicated team was an invaluable experience, reinforcing the belief that determination, ingenuity, and collaboration can lead to extraordinary achievements.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>