<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Business | Portfolio</title><link>https://eidanerlich.github.io/tag/business/</link><atom:link href="https://eidanerlich.github.io/tag/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Business</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://eidanerlich.github.io/media/sharing.png</url><title>Business</title><link>https://eidanerlich.github.io/tag/business/</link></image><item><title>SoilAri, data-driven optimization of small-scale farms</title><link>https://eidanerlich.github.io/project/soilari/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eidanerlich.github.io/project/soilari/</guid><description>&lt;p>Our mission is to leverage data-driven insights to optimize farming for smallholder farmers, who often lack the technical expertise needed to analyze soil and climate data effectively. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the details of SoilAri and how it aims to address critical challenges in the agricultural landscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Problem:
Smallholder farmers play a crucial role in feeding the world&amp;rsquo;s population, yet they face numerous obstacles. In particular, farmers in Sub-Saharan Africa (SSA) are grappling with changing climates and skyrocketing fertilizer costs. With SSA importing 80% of its fertilizer and prices doubling in a year, many farmers can only afford to use a fraction of the required nutrients. These issues are exacerbating poverty and food insecurity in the region.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SoilAri&amp;rsquo;s team recognized the pressing need to address challenges faced by smallholder farmers in SSA, particularly in Kenya. Agriculture contributes approximately 33% of Kenya&amp;rsquo;s GDP, making it a vital sector. Our solution aims to target 220,000 farmers in Kenya during the pilot launch, with the potential to expand our services to more smallholder farms globally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our project involves multiple stakeholders, including individual farmers, their communities, players in the agricultural industry, and the surrounding ecosystems. By empowering farmers with data-driven insights, we anticipate a substantial impact on water and fertilizer usage, leading to more efficient agricultural practices and sustainable resource management.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The core of SoilAri&amp;rsquo;s functionality lies in providing easily digestible data related to irrigation, fertilization based on crop type, and accessibility via simple text messaging. By collecting user input, such as coordinates, farm size, and other relevant data, we leverage APIs and databases to perform calculations and generate targeted insights. Farmers will receive recommendations for optimal fertilization and irrigation practices tailored to their specific needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SoilAri harnesses telemetry data, empowering farmers to make informed decisions. With just a phone and a simple text message, a Kenyan farmer can access valuable information about their location, crop type, and farm size, receiving real-time insights for fertilization and irrigation. This data-driven approach enables farmers to enhance their yields and contribute to sustainable agricultural practices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By partnering with local fertilizer producers, we aim to introduce a 5% commission rate on all sales made through our platform. This revenue, combined with national grants and commissions on fertilization orders, is projected to generate substantial profits over the next five years. We plan to reinvest these profits into supporting small-scale farmers and promoting sustainable agriculture practices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SoilAri envisions a transformative impact in the agricultural landscape, increasing crop yields by 40% and fostering more efficient distribution chains. Our solution aims to enhance food security in the face of formidable challenges. By diversifying revenue streams and fostering collaborations with major contributors, we are confident in our ability to create a positive change in the lives of smallholder farmers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thank you for joining us on this journey as we introduced SoilAri, a groundbreaking project aimed at empowering smallholder farmers in Kenya and beyond. We believe that by harnessing the power of data, we can unlock the potential of sustainable agriculture, contributing to a more resilient and prosperous future for farming communities. If you have any questions or want to learn more, we would be delighted to hear from you. Together, let&amp;rsquo;s sow the seeds of change and cultivate a more sustainable world!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Machine Learning Home Price Prediction</title><link>https://eidanerlich.github.io/project/home-price-prediction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eidanerlich.github.io/project/home-price-prediction/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most noteworthy projects in my portfolio was centered around the application of Python to predict home prices through the implementation of sophisticated supervised machine learning models. The overarching objective was to achieve a high level of precision in forecasting house prices by analyzing pertinent metrics extracted from public datasets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To commence the project, I undertook the task of training two distinct supervised machine learning models. The first model was based on the widely utilized decision tree algorithm, which formed the initial foundation for predicting house prices. The critical challenge at this stage was to determine the optimal decision tree depth that would strike a delicate balance between overfitting and underfitting the data. To address this, I employed a combination of mean absolute error and cross-validation trade-off techniques, allowing me to maximize the model&amp;rsquo;s accuracy while ensuring its generalizability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through this iterative process, I was able to identify the ideal decision tree depth, enhancing the model&amp;rsquo;s performance considerably. Subsequently, I embarked on training and fitting a random forest model to the dataset. The random forest model demonstrated enhanced accuracy when compared to the decision tree model, emerging as the more powerful predictor of house prices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A pivotal aspect of this project was the challenge of acquiring a relevant and robust dataset, along with identifying features that exhibited strong correlations with house prices. To overcome this, I meticulously cleaned and preprocessed the data, implementing feature selection techniques such as variance threshold to isolate the most influential features. By utilizing these selected features as inputs for the machine learning models, and house prices as the target variable, I was able to effectively train the models for accurate predictions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To assess the performance of the models, I employed diverse evaluation metrics, including mean squared error and mean absolute error. The results indicated that the random forest model consistently outperformed the decision tree algorithm, yielding an impressive accuracy rate of +/- 15% compared to the 25% from the decision tree model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In summary, this project showcased my adeptness in applying advanced machine learning techniques to real-world problems. From the meticulous data preprocessing and feature selection to model training and evaluation, the project highlighted my proficiency in Python programming and the effective utilization of machine learning libraries like scikit-learn and pandas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The successful outcome of this project not only reaffirmed my technical prowess but also underscored my ability to approach complex challenges in data analysis and predictive modeling with a methodical and data-driven approach. The experience gained from this project has undoubtedly equipped me to take on future endeavors with unwavering confidence in applying machine learning solutions to various domains, ultimately advancing the field of data science.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Biomedical Instrument R&amp;D</title><link>https://eidanerlich.github.io/project/biomed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://eidanerlich.github.io/project/biomed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine having the chance to embark on an independent research project with an ophthalmologist, exploring cutting-edge technology to revolutionize surgical instruments in ophthalmology. I was fortunate enough to experience just that. This is the story of my endeavor to explore the feasibility of using 3D printing technology to create precise surgical instruments for eye surgeries, the challenges I faced, and the exhilarating successes that followed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The foundation of the project lay in comprehensive research and design. We sought to develop a scleral depressor and a proprietary light cap with custom ends, each serving a unique purpose in surgeries around the eye. It was essential to meticulously investigate various 3D printers, and after thorough evaluation, we opted for the Formlabs 3B+ due to its remarkable precision capabilities. As surgical tools necessitate utmost precision, this choice was critical.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Selecting the right resin was equally vital, and after evaluating several options, it was discovered that Biomed Clear resin offered the required biocompatibility and strength for surgical settings. Ensuring safety was paramount, and this research paved the way for the subsequent phases of our project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the research as the foundation, I delved into the initial development and rapid prototyping stage. Swiftly iterating through designs, I collaborated closely with MD residents, collecting their valuable feedback and using it to refine the prototypes. Root cause analysis and Design of Experiment (DOE) played a crucial role in this phase, enabling us to address issues and enhance the design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Witnessing my creations come to life and being used in real-world surgical settings was an indescribable feeling. It was heartening to see the positive impact our work had on patients, knowing that we were contributing to better outcomes in eye surgeries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was an incredible opportunity to lead a team comprising MD residents and master&amp;rsquo;s students. One of our most notable achievements was the implementation of Design for Manufacture and Assembly (DFMA) principles combined with 3D printing, which remarkably reduced manufacturing costs by over 90%. Witnessing the transformation and cost-effectiveness of our designs was immensely gratifying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to our practical accomplishments, I authored several technical reports, presenting my research findings to the team. These reports will support an upcoming scientific paper and journal publication, ensuring that our work reaches a broader audience and impacts the field of ophthalmology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am incredibly proud to share that the fruits of our labor have not gone unnoticed. The success and potential of our project caught the attention of the University Health Network (UHN), which has taken it up for further growth and development. This development is a testament to the significance and impact of our work in the field of ophthalmology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seeing our project embraced by such a prestigious institution like the UHN is a dream come true. It speaks volumes about the dedication and hard work put into the project by our team. This collaboration opens up a world of possibilities, as the UHN&amp;rsquo;s resources and expertise will undoubtedly propel our project to new heights.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>